Guide to the Pauline Bart papers, 1925-2008 and undated, bulk 1969-1995 RL.10069
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Writings Series, 1963-2005; undated
  - Reviews Subseries, 1973-1993; undated
    - The Physician and Sexuality in Victorian America, 1975; 1 folders (Box 20)
    - The Politics of Victimization (R. Elias), 1989; 1 folders (Box 20)
    - Pornography and Civil Rights, undated; 1 folders (Box 20)
    - Pornography and Sexual Aggression, 1985; 1 folders (Box 20)
    - Psychoanalysis and Women, 1973; 1 folders (Box 20)
    - Rape: A Critical Anthology, undated; 1 folders (Box 20)
    - Rape and Its Victims LEAA, 1975; 1 folders (Box 20)
    - The Rape Victim, 1976; 1 folders (Box 20)
    - Reproduction of Mothering, 1981; 1 folders (Box 20)
    - Right Wing Women, 1983; 1 folders (Box 20)
    - Signs, 1990; 1 folders (Box 20)
    - Their Pleasure Our Danger, 1984; 1 folders (Box 20)
    - Toward a New Psychology of Women, 1976; 1 folders (Box 20)
    - Women and Madness, 1973; 1 folders (Box 20)
    - Women Violence and Social Control/Real Rape/Real Rape on Trial, 1987; 1 folders (Box 20)
    - Womens Review of Books, 1986; 1 folders (Box 20)
    - Miscellaneous reviews, 1976-1991; undated; 1 folders (Box 20)
  - Stopping Rape: Successful Survival Strategies Subseries, 1977-1993; undated
    This subseries contains drafts of Stopping Rape: Successful Survival Strategies, a book Bart co-authored with Patricia H. O'Brien, and other papers related to the book's publication. Published in 1985, Stopping Rape expanded upon research Bart conducted in 1977, when she interviewed 94 survivors of rape or attempted rape in order to generate a list of survival strategies. In addition to chapter drafts, this subseries also includes advertising and publicity related to the book's publication and the underlying research study.
    - Ad Copies, 1977; 1 folders (Box 21)
    - Ads in progress: follow up, 1977; 1 folders (Box 21)
    - Advertisement data, 1977; 1 folders (Box 21)
    - Advertising info, 1977; 1 folders (Box 21)
    - Book chapter notes, undated; 1 folders (Box 21)
    - Book letters, 1982-1983; 1 folders (Box 21)
    - Publicity: Clippings, copies of coverage, 1977; 1 folders (Box 21)
    - Revisions, 1993; 1 folders (Box 21)
    - Stopping Rape: Successful Survival Strategies - Foreword, undated; 1 folders (Box 21)
    - Stopping Rape: Successful Survival Strategies - Chapter 1 draft, undated; 1 folders (Box 21)
    - Stopping Rape: Successful Survival Strategies - Chapter 2 early versions, undated; 1 folders (Box 21)
    - Stopping Rape: Successful Survival Strategies - Chapter 3 early version, undated; 1 folders (Box 21)
    - Stopping Rape: Successful Survival Strategies - Chapter 4 early version, undated; 1 folders (Box 21)
    - Stopping Rape: Successful Survival Strategies - Chapter 5, Settings, undated; 1 folders (Box 21)
    - Stopping Rape: Successful Survival Strategies - Chapter 6 draft, undated; 1 folders (Box 21)
    - Stopping Rape: Successful Survival Strategies - Chapter 7, Ethnicity, undated; 1 folders (Box 22)
    - Stopping Rape: Successful Survival Strategies - Chapter 8 draft, undated; 1 folders (Box 22)
    - Stopping Rape: Successful Survival Strategies - Chapter 9 draft, undated; 1 folders (Box 22)
    - Stopping Rape: Successful Survival Strategies - Appendices, undated; 1 folders (Box 22)
    - Stopping Rape: Successful Survival Strategies - Draft fragments and notes, undated; 2 folders (Box 22)
    - Stopping Rape: Successful Survival Strategies - Unedited draft, undated; 3 folders (Box 22-23)
  - Articles and Academic Papers Subseries, 1963-2005; undated
    The Articles and Academic Paper Subseries contains drafts and printed copies of published and unpublished academic articles and papers written or co-authored by Bart, as well as correspondence, publication information, and other papers related to some articles. Included in this series are drafts and copies of some of Bart's more notable works, including "Portnoy's Mother's Complaint," which grew from Bart's research on depression for her dissertation, "Depression in Middle-Aged Women;" "The Battered Data Syndrome," an article on interpersonal violence and spousal abuse co-authored by Bart, Elizabeth H. Pleck, Joseph H. Pleck, and Marlyn Grossman in response to Suzanne K. Steinmetz's research on battered husbands; "A Funny Thing Happened on the Way to the Orifice," an article about sexist language in gynecology textbooks co-authored by Bart and Diana Scully, and "Seizing the Means of Reproduction," the product of Bart's reserach on the Jane Collective, a feminist underground abortion service in Chicago in the early 1970s.
    - Abortion, Sterilization, Pregnancy and Surrogate Motherhood: Strategies of Control, undated; 1 folders (Box 23)
    - Acquaintance Rape and the Illinois Sexual Assault Statute, 1988; 1 folders (Box 23)
    - The Aftermath of Rape Avoidance, undated; 1 folders (Box 23)
    - Alienation, Women, and Health, undated; 1 folders (Box 23)
    - Anniversary Remarks and Two Poems, 1985; 1 folders (Box 23)
    - Annotated Bibliography of Articles Relevant to the Sociology of Depression, 1967-1970, undated; 1 folders (Box 23)
    - Are You a Housewife or do You Work? Women in Traditional Roles, undated; 1 folders (Box 23)
    - Avoiding Rape, 1978; 1 folders (Box 23)
    - Avoiding Rape: A Study of Victims and Avoiders, 1978; 1 folders (Box 23)
    - The Banned Professor, 1993; 1 folders (Box 23)
    - The Battered Data Syndrome, 1978; 1 folders (Box 23)
    - Being a Feminist Academic, 1981; 1 folders (Box 23)
    - Biological Determinism, undated; 1 folders (Box 23)
    - "But You're Retired": The Loneliness of the Long Distance Sociologist, undated; 1 folders (Box 23)
    - Changing Views of "The Change", circa 1980; 1 folders (Box 24)
    - Collective Work and Self-Identity, 1979; 1 folders (Box 24)
    - Commentary by Bart, 1972-1973; 1 folders (Box 24)
    - Conceptual Framework, undated; 1 folders (Box 24)
    - The Cross-Societal Study of Rape: Some Methodological Problems and Results, 1975; 1 folders (Box 24)
    - Depression: A Sociological Theory, undated; 1 folders (Box 24)
    - Depression in Middle-Aged Women: Some Sociocultural Factors, 1968; 3 folders (Box 24)
    - Depression (sociological aspect, base for "Sociology of Dep"), undated; 1 folders (Box 24)
    - Dirty Books, Dirty Films and Dirty Data, 1978; 1 folders (Box 24)
    - Divorced Men and Their Children, 1970; 1 folders (Box 24)
    - Does Medicine Care about Women?, 1977; 1 folders (Box 24)
    - The Empty Cell: Black on Black Sexual Assault, undated; 1 folders (Box 25)
    - Ethnicity and Rape, 1985; 1 folders (Box 25)
    - An Exercise in the Sociology of Knowledge, 1970; 1 folders (Box 25)
    - Feminist Theories, 1982; 1 folders (Box 25)
    - From Empty Nest to Post-Menopausal Zest, undated; 1 folders (Box 25)
    - From those Wonderful People who Brought You the Vaginal Orgasm, 1976; 1 folders (Box 25)
    - From Wedded Wife to Lesbian Life, undated; 1 folders (Box 25)
    - A Funny Thing Happened on the Way to the Orifice, 1973; 1 folders (Box 25)
    - Gender Differences in Response to "Not a Love Story", 1983; 1 folders (Box 25)
    - Gender and Society Guest Editors' Introduction, 1989; 1 folders (Box 25)
    - A Hard Day at the Orifice, 1972; 1 folders (Box 25)
    - How I Lost my False Consciousness and Found Women's Liberation, 1984; 1 folders (Box 25)
    - How to Say No to Storaska, 1980; 1 folders (Box 25)
    - In the Best Interest of the Sperm, 1987; 1 folders (Box 25)
    - Lectures, 1975-1976; 1 folders (Box 25)
    - Lesbian Research Ethics, undated; 1 folders (Box 25)
    - Letters to the Editor, undated; 1 folders (Box 25)
    - The Loneliness of the Long-Distance Mother, undated; 1 folders (Box 25)
    - Male Power and Female Victimization, undated; 1 folders (Box 25)
    - Male Privilege as an Entitlement Program, 1999; 1 folders (Box 26)
    - Male Views of Female Sexuality, 1974; 1 folders (Box 26)
    - Male Violence Against Women, undated; 1 folders (Box 26)
    - Menopause, undated; 1 folders (Box 26)
    - Mobility and Mental Illness, undated; 1 folders (Box 26)
    - Motherhood Part 2 draft, undated; 1 folders (Box 26)
    - The Myth of a Value-Free Psychotherapy, 1972; 1 folders (Box 26)
    - The New Sex Education and the Women's Movement, undated; 1 folders (Box 26)
    - Notes from a Formerly Nice Jewish Girl, 1995; 1 folders (Box 26)
    - Pioneers, Professionals, Returnees, Penelopes, and Portnoy's Mothers, 1973; 1 folders (Box 26)
    - Poetry, undated; 1 folders (Box 26)
    - Politics of Hysteria, undated; 1 folders (Box 26)
    - Pornography: Hating Women and Institutionalizing Dominance and Submission for Fun and Profit, 1986; 1 folders (Box 26)
    - Portnoy's Mother's Complaint: appendix, undated; 1 folders (Box 26)
    - Portnoy's Mother's Complaint: draft, undated; 1 folders (Box 26)
    - Post-Maternal Roles Available to Women, 1963; 1 folders (Box 27)
    - Radical Feminisms, 1988; 1 folders (Box 27)
    - Rape and the Criminal Justice System, 1975; 1 folders (Box 27)
    - Rape as a Paradigm of Sexism in Society, 1979; 1 folders (Box 27)
    - Rape Doesn't End with a Kiss, 1975; 1 folders (Box 27)
    - "Rape is Not Funny", 1977; 1 folders (Box 27)
    - Rape Lectures, undated; 1 folders (Box 27)
    - Recommendations of the Citizens Advisory Council on Rape, 1975; 1 folders (Box 27)
    - Report of the Hospital Subcomittee on Rape, undated; 1 folders (Box 27)
    - The Role of the Sociologist on Public Issues, 1970; 1 folders (Box 27)
    - Roles Without Rules, 1972; 1 folders (Box 27)
    - Seizing the Means of Reproduction, 1977; 1 folders (Box 27)
    - Seizing the Means of Reproduction: review, undated; 1 folders (Box 27)
    - Sex Roles and Health Issues, undated; 1 folders (Box 27)
    - Sexism and Social Science: From the Gilded Cage to the Iron Cage, or, the Perils of Pauline, 1971; 1 folders (Box 27)
    - The Sexually Emancipated Woman, undated; 1 folders (Box 28)
    - Social Structure and Vocabularies of Discomfort, 1968; 1 folders (Box 28)
    - Socio-Cultural Factors in Hospitalized Depressive Reactions of Middle-Aged Women, undated; 1 folders (Box 28)
    - The Sociology of Depression, 1974; 1 folders (Box 28)
    - Stopping Rape: Effective Avoidance Strategies, 1984; 1 folders (Box 28)
    - A Study of Women who Both Were Raped and Avoided Rape, 1978; 1 folders (Box 28)
    - Taking the Men out of Menopause, undated; 1 folders (Box 28)
    - Taking Our Bodies Back, 1977; 1 folders (Box 28)
    - Talk to Latinos/as, undated; 1 folders (Box 28)
    - Talks and presentations, 1969-1973; undated; 1 folders (Box 28)
    - Testimony before legislative committee on rape, undated; 1 folders (Box 28)
    - There Ought to be a Law, 1980; 1 folders (Box 28)
    - Things Fall Apart, 2005; 1 folders (Box 28)
    - Through Women's Eyes: Defining Danger in the Wake of Sexual Assault, 1982; 1 folders (Box 28)
    - True Stories of Ethics, undated; 1 folders (Box 28)
    - Unalienating Abortion, Demystifying Depression, and Restoring Rape Victims, 1975; 1 folders (Box 28)
    - Victimization and its Discontents, 1978; 1 folders (Box 28)
    - What to do after being Raped, undated; 1 folders (Box 28)
    - What the Women in the Hospitals were Like: the Marginal Distributions, undated; 1 folders (Box 28)
    - Why Men Rape, 1983; 1 folders (Box 29)
    - Why a Nice Jewish Girl Like Me Loves the Nuns, undated; 1 folders (Box 29)
    - Why Women See the Future Differently From Men, 1974; 1 folders (Box 29)
    - Why Women's Status Changes in Middle Age, 1969; 1 folders (Box 29)
    - Woman as Victim and Perpetrator of Violence, 1984; 1 folders (Box 29)
    - Woman to Woman: Is Sisterhood Powerful?, undated; 1 folders (Box 29)
    - Women and Abuse, undated; 1 folders (Box 29)
    - Women Abuse and Sociology, undated; 1 folders (Box 29)
    - Women and Health Care, 1973; 1 folders (Box 29)
    - Working Mothers paper draft, undated; 1 folders (Box 29)
    - Fragments and unlabeled drafts, undated; 1 folders (Box 29)
  - Other Writing Materials Subseries, 1974-1995; undated
    This subseries largely consists of papers related to Bart's writings, including book contracts, reprint requests, and reviews.
    - Book Contracts forthcoming, 1988; 1 folders (Box 29)
    - Contract with the Free Press, 1979; 1 folders (Box 29)
    - Crossing Press, undated; 1 folders (Box 29)
    - Final report, requests for copies, 1980-1981; 1 folders (Box 29)
    - Modular Publications contract, 1974; 1 folders (Box 29)
    - Reprint requests, 1975-1983; 3 folders (Box 29-30)
    - Reviews of Bart, 1986-1995; 1 folders (Box 30)
    - Tee Corinne, 1991; 1 folders (Box 30)
- Teaching Materials Series, 1968-1995; undated
  The Teaching Materials Series contains papers related to classes taught by Bart at the University of Illinois in Chicago, the University of California at Los Angeles, and other institutions. Materials include syllabi, lists and copies of course readings, student papers, and other papers.
  - Attitudes Toward Strike Soc115, undated; 1 folders (Box 30)
  - Books for Violence Against Women, 1991-1992; 1 folders (Box 30)
  - Class lists and syllabi, 1986-1988; undated; 1 folders (Box 30)
  - Class lists, 1995; 1 folders (Box 30)
  - Classes spring 1991-1992, 1 folders (Box 30)
  - Cultural studies, 1970s; 1 folders (Box 30)
  - Gender and Society, 1969-1992; 1 folders (Box 31)
  - Fall '89 class material, 1989; 1 folders (Box 31)
  - Feminist Jurisprudence, undated; 1 folders (Box 31)
  - Feminist Literary Criticism, 1986; 1 folders (Box 31)
  - Feminist Theory, 1968; 1 folders (Box 31)
  - Final exam, Violence Against Women, undated; 1 folders (Box 31)
  - Jewish Women course, 1991-1992; 1 folders (Box 31)
  - Jewish Women's Health and Violence class, 1980; undated; 1 folders (Box 31)
  - Materials for women's course, 1969; undated; 1 folders (Box 31)
  - Med Students, 1981-1988; 1 folders (Box 31)
  - Med students course, 1994; 1 folders (Box 31)
  - Previously taught courses, 1989-1992; 1 folders (Box 32)
  - Rape Protocol U.I. of Illinois, 1975; 1 folders (Box 32)
  - Residents: Violence Against Women, undated; 1 folders (Box 32)
  - Sex Roles and Violence Against Women, undated; 1 folders (Box 32)
  - Soc489 Violence Against Women, 1978; 1 folders (Box 32)
  - Soc489, 1979; 1 folders (Box 32)
  - Soc489, 1980-1984; 1 folders (Box 32)
  - Soc489, 1986; 1 folders (Box 32)
  - Soc489 and IWY Stuff, 1977-1978; undated; 1 folders (Box 32)
  - Sociology 102D: Feminist Theory, undated; 1 folders (Box 32)
  - Sociology class materials, 1980-1995; 1 folders (Box 32)
  - Sociology courses, undated; 1 folders (Box 32)
  - Spring '89 class stuff (Feminist Theory), 1989; 1 folders (Box 33)
  - Student papers, 1980-1985; 1 folders (Box 33)
  - Student surveys, undated; 1 folders (Box 33)
  - Studies for meeting tomorrow, undated; 1 folders (Box 33)
  - Syllabi, 1979-1980; 1 folders (Box 33)
  - Teaching clippings, 1991; 1 folders (Box 33)
  - Teaching women's studies, undated; 1 folders (Box 33)
  - UCLA, 1995; 1 folders (Box 33)
  - Women and Health syllabi, 1973; undated; 1 folders (Box 33)
  - Women class essays, undated; 1 folders (Box 33)
  - WS494 Violence Against Women, 1992; 1 folders (Box 33)
  - Loose teaching materials, 1969-1995; undated; 2 folders (Box 33)
- Research Files Series, 1961-1995; undated; 4
  The Research Files Series contains interview transcripts, content analysis, and other papers related to the Jane Collective, which Bart researched in pursuit of her article "Seizing the Means of Reproduction: An Illegal Feminist Abortion Collective - How and Why it Worked;" materials related to Stopping Rape: Successful Survival Strategies, including transcripts of interviews with 94 survivors of sexual assault or attempted rape, notebooks containing content analysis of the interviews, grant applications and drafts, Viva rape questionnaires, and other papers; interview transcripts and other papers related to a study of depression; and other research files on topics such as pornography, depression, violence against women, the Illinois sexual assault statute, feminism, rape, and homosexuality.
  - Jane Collective Research Subseries, 1969-1990; undated
    The Jane Collective Research Subseries contains papers related to Bart's research on the Abortion Counseling Service of Women's Liberation, also known as the Jane Collective, a feminist underground abortion service operating in Chicago, Illinois from 1969-1973. Founded by University of Chicago student Heather Booth, the Jane Collective provided more than 11,000 women with abortions and abortion counseling prior to abortion being legalized by Roe v. Wade in 1973.
    Bart interviewed members of the Jane Collective in pursuit of her article, "Seizing the Means of Reproduction." The materials in this subseries include interview transcripts, Bart's content analysis and notes on the interviews, drafts and draft fragments of "Seizing the Means of Reproduction," and some correspondence. Some interviews also include audio recordings. See the Audiotapes Series for more information.
    Access Restrictions
    Boxes 36-39 are closed to researchers until 2039. Redacted versions of interview transcripts in this subseries are available for use; see boxes 35 and 91.
    - Arcana and Bart, undated; 1 folders (Box 34)
    - Booth, Heather, undated; 1 folders (Box 34)
    - Coding Categories, undated; 1 folders (Box 34)
    - Demographics, undated; 1 folders (Box 34)
    - Jane subject (comparative), undated; 1 folders (Box 34)
    - Parsons, Jody, undated; 1 folders (Box 34)
    - Seizing the Means of Reproduction drafts and draft fragments, undated; 1 folders (Box 34)
    - Seizing the Means of Reproduction unedited drafts, undated; 1 folders (Box 34)
    - Ruth Surgal, undated; 1 folders (Box 34)
    - Judy Wiltner, undated; 1 folders (Box 34)
    - Loose materials on Jane, 1969-1990; undated; 1 folders (Box 34)
    - Redacted interview transcripts 1-20, 20 folders (Box 35)
    - Redacted interview transcripts 21-40, 20 folders (Box 91)
    - Restricted materials
      Closed to researchers until 2039.
      - Index to redacted interview transcripts, 1 folders (Box 36)
      - Interviews with members of the Jane Collective, 1976; undated; 4 boxes (Box 36-38)
      - Abortion as Murder, undated; 1 folders (Box 38)
      - Bust, undated; 1 folders (Box 38)
      - Children, undated; 1 folders (Box 38)
      - Correspondence between Mildred Davis and Pauline Bart, plus notes, 1976; undated; 1 folders (Box 38)
      - Counseling, undated; 1 folders (Box 38)
      - Dealing with Incompetence, undated; 1 folders (Box 38)
      - Death of Woman, undated; 1 folders (Box 38)
      - Excerpts from Interview Transcripts, undated; 1 folders (Box 38)
      - Excepts of interviews discussing members' personal roles, undated; 1 folders (Box 38)
      - Feminism, undated; 1 folders (Box 39)
      - How changed chapt., undated; 1 folders (Box 39)
      - How got in, undated; 1 folders (Box 39)
      - How learned, undated; 1 folders (Box 39)
      - How worked, undated; 1 folders (Box 39)
      - Illegality use, undated; 1 folders (Box 39)
      - Illegality not using, undated; 1 folders (Box 39)
      - Interpersonal relations: best liked least liked, undated; 1 folders (Box 39)
      - Jane correspondence, undated; 1 folders (Box 39)
      - Janes call back and big, undated; 1 folders (Box 39)
      - Lawyer, undated; 1 folders (Box 39)
      - Lesbians, undated; 1 folders (Box 39)
      - Long terms, undated; 1 folders (Box 39)
      - Loose notes on Jane, undated; 1 folders (Box 39)
      - Male A.B., undated; 1 folders (Box 39)
      - Money, undated; 1 folders (Box 39)
      - Names, undated; 1 folders (Box 39)
      - Org of Services, undated; 1 folders (Box 39)
      - Other, undated; 1 folders (Box 39)
      - Physicians medical mystique, undated; 1 folders (Box 39)
      - Personal experience with A.B., undated; 1 folders (Box 39)
      - Polit Phil., undated; 1 folders (Box 39)
      - Self Perception, undated; 1 folders (Box 39)
      - To be Xeroxed, undated; 1 folders (Box 39)
      - Was it a collective, undated; 1 folders (Box 39)
      - What doing now, undated; 1 folders (Box 39)
      - Why it worked, undated; 1 folders (Box 39)
  - Rape Avoidance Research Subseries, 1974-1990; undated
    The Rape Avoidance Research Subseries contains materials related to Bart's book, Stopping Rape: Successful Survival Strategies. Papers include transcripts of anonymous interviews with 94 surivors of rape and attempted rape, including 9 pilot interviews, code books, materials related to grants that funded the study, interview schedules, notebooks containing Bart's content analysis and notes on the interviews, Viva Magazine Rape Questionnaires, and other papers.
    - Pilot interviews, 1977; 8 folders (Box 40)
    - Subjects 1-3, 1977; 3 folders (Box 40)
    - Subjects 4-11, 1977; 8 folders (Box 41)
    - Subjects 12-19, 1977; 8 folders (Box 42)
    - Subjects 20-26, 1977; 7 folders (Box 43)
    - Subjects 27-35, 1977; 9 folders (Box 44)
    - Subjects 36-42, 1977; 7 folders (Box 45)
    - Subjects 43-51, 1977; 9 folders (Box 46)
    - Subjects 52-58, 1977; 7 folders (Box 47)
    - Subjects 59-67, 1977; 9 folders (Box 48)
    - Subjects 68-76, 1977; 9 folders (Box 49)
    - Subjects 77-86, 1977; 10 folders (Box 50)
    - Subjects 87-94, 1977; 8 folders (Box 51)
    - Addendum: Revised interview schedule, self-report questionnare, undated; 1 folders (Box 52)
    - Adult consent form "Avoiding Rape?", undated; 1 folders (Box 52)
    - Advocate meetings, undated; 1 folders (Box 52)
    - Aggravating factors- Judge LaCallo's Lecture, undated; 1 folders (Box 52)
    - All Post, 1977; 1 folders (Box 52)
    - Alleged sex assault report, undated; 1 folders (Box 52)
    - APA Rape, undated; 1 folders (Box 52)
    - Appendix materials, 1986-1988; undated; 1 folders (Box 52)
    - Civil Cases, 1989; undated; 1 folders (Box 52)
    - Code Book, undated; 1 folders (Box 52)
    - Code Book 2, undated; 1 folders (Box 52)
    - Consent forms, 1977; 1 folders (Box 52)
    - Continuation Application, 1977; 1 folders (Box 52)
    - Data (rape), undated; 1 folders (Box 52)
    - Effect (also in police file), 1974; 1 folders (Box 52)
    - Either pre or post, 1977; 1 folders (Box 52)
    - First draft (grant), 1976; 1 folders (Box 52)
    - Forms for ER Research, undated; 1 folders (Box 52)
    - Grant #MH-29311/1980 NIMH, 1 folders (Box 52)
    - Grant extension, additional monies, 1977; 1 folders (Box 53)
    - Grant paper, 1980; 1 folders (Box 53)
    - Grant: second draft, 1976; 1 folders (Box 53)
    - Human subjects, 1976; 1 folders (Box 53)
    - Interview schedule and consent forms, undated; 1 folders (Box 53)
    - Interview with P.D., undated; 1 folders (Box 53)
    - Letters from rape victims, undated; 1 folders (Box 53)
    - Letters in response to Viva survey, 1974; 1 folders (Box 53)
    - List of cases used in each chapter and context in which the case was presented, undated; 1 folders (Box 53)
    - Martha's notes, undated; 1 folders (Box 53)
    - Misdemeanor court meetings, undated; 1 folders (Box 53)
    - Mother's quote "See how dogs men is", undated; 1 folders (Box 53)
    - NIMH forms, undated; 1 folders (Box 53)
    - Notebooks, undated; 4 boxes (Box 53-56)
    - Notice on grant extension, 1979; 1 folders (Box 56)
    - Organizational support (letters), 1976; 1 folders (Box 56)
    - Other attack when in life cycle, undated; 1 folders (Box 56)
    - Other related grant material, 1977; 1 folders (Box 56)
    - P. Robinson, 1990; 1 folders (Box 56)
    - Pauline's notes, undated; 1 folders (Box 56)
    - Police, undated; 1 folders (Box 56)